esc13.net 2004-06-18

# Region XIII Education Service Center Website Privacy Statement

   Region XIII Education Service Center Website Privacy Statement
                 ©2004 Region XIII Education Service Center (Region XIII ESC)
INTRODUCTION: Region XIII ESC maintains the Region XIII ESC website (esc13.net) as a
public service. This privacy statement demonstrates our commitment to the privacy of our
users and the personal information they share with Region XIII.
This privacy statement explains the data collection and use practices of Region XIII ESC for all
publicly accessible pages in the esc13.net domain; it does not apply to other online or offline
sites, products, or services. The choices you make on this website will not necessarily apply to
personally identifiable information you may have provided to Region XIII ESC in the context of
other, separately operated Region XIII ESC products or services.
By using this site, you agree with the terms of this privacy statement. Whenever you submit
information via this site, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of that information in
accordance with this statement.
As we continue to develop our website and take advantage of technologies to improve the
services we provide, we reserve the right to change this privacy statement at any time and
without notice. Therefore, we encourage you to refer to this statement on an ongoing basis.
This privacy statement was last updated on May 10, 2004.
COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION: From the
Contact, Application, and Registration sections of the website you may choose to share
“personally identifiable information” with us to process a request for information or assistance.
The term "personally identifiable information" means any information that could reasonably be
used to identify you such as your name, address, e-mail address, phone number(s), Social
Security number, driver’s license number, occupational or professional license numbers, birth
date, financial information, any information that is linked to or associated with identifiable
information, or any combination of information that could be used for identification purposes.
For all other browsing, users are not asked for “personally identifiable information” and none will
be collected.
We use “personally identifiable information” collected from the Contact, Application, and
Registration sections of the website to communicate with you, conduct online transactions
between you and Region XIII ESC via the website, respond to your request, notify you of
updates or changes, forward additional information about related services, and deliver other
customer services.
Where you pay for registration or application services online with a credit card or online check,
the personally identifiable information entered in these transactions is used only for the
purposes described in that transaction, unless an additional use is specifically stated on that
page.
Personally identifiable information collected on this site may be stored and processed in the
United States or any other country in which Region XIII ESC or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or
agents maintain facilities; by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information
outside of your country.
Users are reminded that any personally identifiable information that is voluntarily posted by a
user to a public area of this web site (for example, a posting to a bulletin board or chat room)

may always be collected and used by others using the same bulletin board or chat room. We
cannot prevent such uses.
COLLECTION AND USE OF STATISTICAL DATA: For site management functions, information
is collected for analysis and statistical purposes. This information is not reported or used in any
manner that would reveal personally identifiable information. Our web servers generate
temporary logs that contain the following information:
    _ Internet address of computer being used (IP address)
    _ Web pages requested
    _ Referring web page
    _ Browser used
    _ Operating system used
    _ Date and time
The data is used to generate reports showing general numbers of activity with our website. The
data can also be used to tune the website for its efficiency, such as assessing what information
is of most interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system
performance or problem areas. Raw data from the web server logs is only shared with the
server manager of each web server. Summary reports produced from the logs help web server
managers determine what web browsers and pages are most popular and what hours are
consistently high usage hours.
SECURITY OF INFORMATION: Although no computer system is 100% secure, Region XIII
ESC has deployed extensive security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration
of the information under our control.
Region XIII ESC strictly protects the security of the personally identifiable information you
provide. Personal information we collect is stored in password-controlled servers with limited
access, and we carefully protect this information from loss or misuse, and from unauthorized
access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.
Several sites within the Region XIII ESC website enable you to pay for registration or application
services online with a credit card or online check. Unless otherwise noted, these transactions are
encrypted.
This website does not encrypt incoming e-mail, so you should not send information that you
consider highly sensitive through it.
Region XIII ESC will not share or release information about you to any third parties without your
explicit consent. We will not share or sell your e-mail addresses with anyone outside of Region
XIII ESC with the exception of an annual report to Texas Education Agency. However, Region
XIII ESC may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief
that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal
process served on Region XIII ESC; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Region XIII
ESC; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Region XIII
ESC, its websites, or the public.
USE OF COOKIES: Cookies are small files that a web server/website places on your computer
hard drive to assist in distinguishing your browser from a previous visitor by saving and
remembering any preferences that set while visiting a specific site.
While the Region XIII ESC website will not require the use of cookie files or cookies to view
public information, the Region XIII ESC website may require the use of cookies to facilitate

applications and registrations that display user-specific web pages. Information gathered
through the use of cookies will only be used by the Region XIII ESC website to facilitate the
display of information to the web user and for collection of information that the web user is
submitting.
ACCESS TO AND RELEASE OF INFORMATION: With a few exceptions, you have the right to
be informed about the information that the Region XIII ESC website collects about you, the right
to request a copy of that information, and to have Region XIII ESC correct any information that
is wrong. Please note that information provided to the Region XIII ESC website may be subject
to public disclosure under the Texas Public Information Act or applicable federal legislation
unless a specific statutory exception applies.
CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT: We may occasionally update this privacy
statement. When we do, we will revise the “last updated” date in the Introduction section of the
privacy statement. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay
informed about how we are protecting the personally identifiable information we collect. Your
continued use of the website constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any
updates.
SPECIAL NOTICE TO PARENTS: While Region XIII ESC realizes children are active on the
Internet, we do not knowingly seek or collect information from minors who visit this website.
Nevertheless, we encourage you to ask your children to seek your permission before providing
information about themselves or their family over the Internet.
In the event information is inadvertently collected from a minor, the personally identifiable
information submitted by the minor will not be used for further marketing and promotion if we
are able to identify a user as a minor. The same privacy policies will apply to that information.
SPECIAL NOTICE TO CHILDREN: Ask your parent or guardian for permission before you send
any personal information over the Internet.
QUESTIONS OR COMMENTS: Region XIII ESC welcomes your comments regarding this
privacy statement. If you have questions about this privacy statement or you believe that your
personal information has been released without your consent, please send an e-mail to the
webmaster at webmaster@esc13.txed.net.
